<document>
  <properties>
	<title>Vulcan - Installation Overview</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
	<section name="Overview">
		<p>
			Vulcan requires some Java components to be installed on your machine before Vulcan itself
			can be installed.  There are many options which can satisfy these dependencies, and this
			document refers to the most common or likely choices.
		</p>
	</section>
	<section name="Java Runtime Environment">
		<p>
			First, you will need a Java Runtime Environment, version 5.0 or later.  If you already
			have either the JDK or JRE installed, skip to the next section.
		</p>
		<p>
			Download the JRE from Sun Microsystems at <a href="http://java.sun.com">http://java.sun.com</a>.
		</p>
		<p>
			<span class="note">Note:  It is not necessary to install the web browser integration
			when installing the JRE.</span>
		</p>
		<p>
			When you install the JRE, make a note of where it was installed, since you may need
			to reference this location when installing Apache Tomcat.
		</p>
	</section>
	<section name="Web Application Server">
		<p>
			Vulcan requires a JEE 1.4 compliant Web Application Server.  The best open source option is to use
			Apache Tomcat 5.5 or later, available from <a href="http://tomcat.apache.org">http://tomcat.apache.org</a>.
			When following the setup,
			make sure that the JRE you installed in the previous section is selected for use with Tomcat.
		</p>
		<p>
			If you are installing on Microsoft Windows, you will have the option to install Apache Tomcat
			as a Windows Service.  This is recommended because it will allow Apache Tomcat to automatically
			start when the computer boots.
		</p>
	</section>
	<section name="Download Vulcan">
		<p>
			Use the download link in the left-hand menu to download the latest stable version of Vulcan.
		</p>
	</section>
	<section name="Unpack Vulcan">
		<p>
			Although you can take the the WAR file you downloaded and deploy it directly, it is recommended
			that you unpack the WAR file so you can apply configuration settings before you install Vulcan.
		</p>
		<p>
			The file you downloaded (vulcan.war) is really just a ZIP file with a different extension.  You
			can unpack it using any software that supports the ZIP format.
		</p>
		<p>
			In Microsoft Windows, you may need to rename <span class="filename">vulcan.war</span> to
			<span class="filename">vulcan.zip</span> so programs will recognize it.  Afterwards, you
			should be able to open the archive using either Windows Explorer (using the Compressed Folder
			capability) or in WinZip.
		</p>
		<p>
			In Linux and other operating systems, you can simply use the "unzip" command to extract the files.
		</p>
		<p>
			<span class="note">Note:  Make sure to create a new folder to use when unpacking Vulcan,
			because the archive itself does not create a subdirectory.</span>
		</p>
	</section>
	<section name="Vulcan Pre-deployment Steps">
		<p>
			Vulcan comes configured with default settings which you may wish to customize.  Some of these
			settings should be applied before you deploy Vulcan.  If you plan to enable security, which is
			recommended, or if you would like Vulcan to store its configuration files somewhere other than
			the default location, you will have to modify files in the Vulcan WAR (Web Application Archive)
			before deployment.
		</p>
		<p>
			Read the <a href="security.html">Security Configuration</a> and
			<a href="custom.html">Advanced Customization</a> sections now, before deploying Vulcan.
		</p>
	</section>
	<section name="Deploy Vulcan">
		<p>
			At this point you should have the JRE installed, Apache Tomcat installed and running, and 
			Vulcan configured for your security needs.  Now it is time to deploy Vulcan.
		</p>
		<p>
			You will be using the Apache Tomcat Manager application to deploy Vulcan.  However, for
			security reasons, Apache Tomcat must be configured before you can access this application.
			See the <a href="http://tomcat.apache.org/tomcat-5.5-doc/manager-howto.html">Apache Tomcat Manager Howto</a>
			for instructions on how to do this.
		</p>
		<p>
			Access the Apache Tomcat Manager application by directing a web browser to
			<a href="http://localhost:8080/manager/html">http://localhost:8080/manager/html</a>.
		</p>
		<p>
			After you log in, find the text box labelled <span class="label">WAR or Directory URL</span>
			and enter the directory where you unpacked Vulcan.
		</p>
		<p>
			If you would like Vulcan to reside
			at the root of your Tomcat server, enter <span class="filename">/</span>
			in the text box labelled
			<span class="label">Context Path</span>.  Otherwise, enter <span class="filename">/vulcan</span>.
		</p>
		<p>
			Click the Deploy button.  When the page refreshes, you should see Vulcan in the
			list of applications.  Click the link to navigate over to Vulcan.
		</p>
	</section>
  </body>
</document>
