<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Vulcan Build Manager</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Overview">
    	<p>
    		An incremental build is defined as a build that is performed while existing intermediate
    		artifacts are already built.  These intermediate artifacts (class files, jars, assemblies, etc.)
    		may be used without being rebuilt if your build process believes that they are up to date.
    	</p>
    	
    	<p>
    		Incremental builds can reduce build time in 2 places.  First, instead of deleting the working
    		copy completely, an existing working copy may be updated with any changes that are found in
    		your source repository.  If you have a very large project, this can dramatically reduce the time
    		taken interacting with your source repository.  Additionally, if your build tool must compile
    		a large amount of source files, time can be saved by only compiling source files which have
    		changed.
    	</p>
    	
    	<p>
    		While incremental builds provide speed-up benefits, they also have some risky side effects.
    		Ultimately, it comes down to how much you trust your build scripts and build tools to detect
    		changes and rebuild everything that needs to be rebuilt.  However, anecdotal evidence suggests
    		that incremental builds can sometimes produce spurious errors that simply go away by cleaning
    		all intermediate artifacts and performing a full build.  For this reason, it is recommended that
    		incremental builds be avoided in almost all cases.
    	</p>
    </section>
    <section name="Vulcan Support For Incremental Builds">
    	<p>
    		Vulcan allows you to perform incremental builds in 2 places.  First, in
    		<a href="configuration/projects.html">project configuration</a> you can 
    		configure your project to use incremental builds on a regular basis.  Second,
    		you can override the project default when performing a
    		<a href="manualbuild.html">manual build</a>.
    	</p>
    	<p>
    		There are some cases in which Vulcan will perform a full build even though an
    		incremental build was requested.  If any of the following criteria are detected,
    		a full build will be performed:
    	</p>
    	<ul>
    		<li>Working Copy location does not exist or is empty</li>
    		<li>Previous build does not exist</li>
    		<li>Previous build oucome resulted in ERROR</li>
			<li>Previous build used an alternate branch/tag (see <a href="manualbuild.html">manual build</a>)</li>
    	</ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
