<document>
  <properties>
	<title>Vulcan - Advanced Customization</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
	<section name="Overview">
		<p>
			Projects can be created, modified and deleted through Vulcan's web interface.  Click
			the <span class="location">Setup</span> link in the top menu on the Vulcan dashboard.
		</p>
		<p>
			To create a new project, click <spac class="location">New Project</spac> in the
			left-hand menu.  You can review and modify existing project configuration by
			clicking the project of interest in the same menu.
		</p>
		<p>
			<span class="note">Note:</span> If this is the first time you are configuring
			Vulcan, you should probably configure your Repository Adaptor Plugins and
			Build Tool Plugins before creating new projects.
		</p>
	</section>
	<section name="Configuration Options">
		<p>
			The Project Configuration screen allows you to enter the following
			information about your project.
		</p>
		<table>
			<thead>
				<tr>
					<th>Field</th>
					<th>Required</th>
					<th>Description</th>
				</tr>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<tr>
					<td>Project Name</td>
					<td class="required">Yes</td>
					<td>The name you want to use to identify your project within Vulcan.
						You may use mixed-case letters, numbers, hyphens and underscores.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Working Copy Directory</td>
					<td class="required">Yes</td>
					<td>The location to use when checking out files from your repository.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Site Index</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>Vulcan allows users to browse the working copy of the most recent
						build.  If you have a landing page in the workig copy, you can
						configure the link from the build details page to link directly
						to that page.  For example, if you use Apache Maven and generate a
						site, you could use "target/site/index.html" for this value.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Bugtraq URL</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>If your team has a web-enabled issue tracker, you can configure
						this setting so Vulcan will link to issues that are mentioned
						in commit logs.  If you use Bugzilla, enter something like:
						<code>http://bugzilla.example.com/show_bug.cgi?id=%BUGID%</code>
						Vulcan will replace %BUGID% with the issue ID so you can link
						directly to the issue that was mentioned.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Bugtraq Keyword Regex</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>This regular expression will be used to parse issue/bug IDs out
						out of commit messages.  A typical example is:
						<code>bug (\d+)</code>
						However, if you may want to match other keywords (like "issue"),
						and be more flexible.  A very flexible pattern is:
						<code>([Bb]ug|[Ii]ssue):? ?#?(\d+)</code>
						This pattern would match any of the following strings:
						<ul>
							<li>bug #12</li>
							<li>Bug 43</li>
							<li>issue: 56</li>
							<li>Issue56</li>
						</ul>
						If a Bugtraq ID Regex is not specified, the last capture group
						must match the numeric bug ID.
						
						<span class="note">
							If you are using Subversion, you may have these settings defined
							in your repository.  In that case, instead of repeating them here,
							you can configure the Vulcan Subversion plugin to obtain these
							settings from your working copy.  See 
							<a href="../plugins/subversion">Subversion Plugin</a> documentation
							for more details.
						</span>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Bugtraq ID Regex</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>This field should be set only if you wish to match multiple issue/bug IDs
						after a single keyword.  For example, if you want to match the message:
						<code>Fixes for bugs 12, 14, and 42.</code>
						In this case, the Bugtraq Keyword Regex should match the entire string
						"bugs 12, 14, and 42" and the Bugtraq ID Regex should match each issue/bug
						ID within that string.  An example for the Bugtraq Pattern Regex:
						<code>bugs #?(\d+)(,? ?(and)? ?#?(\d+))+</code>
						In most cases, the Bugtraq ID Regex should simply be set to:
						<code>\d+</code>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Repository Adaptor</td>
					<td class="required">Yes</td>
					<td>The plugin to use which will integrate with your source repository.
						Choose from the available plugins, then you must click the
						<span class="location">Configure</span> button to enter
						information specific to the adaptor.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Build Tool</td>
					<td class="required">Yes</td>
					<td>The plugin to use which will build your project.  Choose from
						the available plugins, then you must click the
						<span class="location">Configure</span> button to enter
						information specific to the build tool.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Dependencies</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>If you are building more than one project with Vulcan, and some
						projects depend on others, you can express those dependencies here.
						Vulcan will automatically build your projects in the correct order.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Build Options</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>This section has several options which should be self-explanatory.
						The first option is useful if you have many dependencies and don't want
						to assign each individual project to a scheduler.  By checking this option
						on your highest level projects, the dependencies will automatically be
						queued for build even though they are not assigned to a scheduler.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Update Policy</td>
					<td>Yes</td>
					<td>This section allows you to configure incremental builds for your project.
						See the section on <a href="../incrementalbuilds.html">incremental builds</a>
						before changing the default setting.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Build Scheduler</td>
					<td class="required">Yes</td>
					<td>This is where you assign a project to be added to the build queue
						when the selected scheduler fires.  If you do not want your project
						to be built on a periodic schedule, leave the default value of
						<span class="location">none</span>.
					</td>
				</tr>
			</tbody>
		</table>
	</section>
  </body>
</document>
