<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Ant Plugin for Vulcan Build Manager</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Project Configuration">
		<table>
			<thead>
				<tr>
					<th>Field</th>
					<th>Required</th>
					<th>Description</th>
				</tr>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<tr>
					<td>Build Script</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>If your project build script is named something other than build.xml, or is not in the top level directory,
					you can specify a relative path to your build script.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Target(s)</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>You can override your build script's default target by specifying targets here, separated by spaces.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Java Home</td>
					<td class="required">Yes</td>
					<td>Select which Java Home to use to run Ant.  New profiles can be defined in the Ant plugin global configuration.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Verbose Logging</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>Check this box to pass the switch <span class="keyword">-verbose</span> to Ant.  This will result in a much larger
					build log, useful for troubleshooting when your build script is not working.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Debug Logging</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>Check this box to pass the switch <span class="keyword">-debug</span> to Ant.  This will result in a much larger
					build log, useful for troubleshooting when Verbose Logging does not provide enough insight to resolve a build script
					issue.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Ant Properties</td>
					<td>No</td>
					<td>Properties, in the form name=value.  Properties defined here will be added to properties defined in the global Ant plugin
					configuration.  Project properties will override global property values.  It is not necessary to include the -D switch which
					is used on the command line to define an Ant property, although if you do this the plugin will still correctly configure the property.</td>
				</tr>
			</tbody>
		</table>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
