<document>
  <properties>
	<title>Vulcan - Advanced Customization</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
	<section name="Overview">
		<p>
			Most of Vulcan configuration can be accomplished using the Setup section of the application.
			However, there are a few settings which require you to make changes manually.  Most users
			will not need to modify these settings.
		</p>
		<p>
			The advanced settings are stored in an XML file under the location where you unpacked
			Vulcan, in a sub-directory named <span class="filename">WEB-INF</span>, called
			<span class="filename">beans.xml</span>.  Many of the configuratin values in this
			file should not be modified (or Vulcan may stop working).  However, the following
			sections indicate some of the settings which you may want to customize.
		</p>
	</section>
	<section name="Vulcan Home">
		<p>
			Vulcan uses a directory to store configuration data about your projects, including build
			outcomes and plugin data.  By default Vulcan will use:
		</p>
		<table>
			<thead>
				<tr>
					<th>Operating System</th>
					<th class="location">Location</th>
					<th>Details</th>
				</tr>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<tr>
					<td>Windows</td>
					<td class="location">%USERPROFILE%\Application Data\vulcan</td>
					<td>
						If you run Vulcan as a normal user, configuration data will go in the
						<span class="filename">C:\Documents and Settings\username\Application Data\vulacn</span>.
						If you run Vulcan as a Windows Service, by default it will run as LocalSystem.  Since that 
						account does not have a 
						home directory, Vulcan configuration will end up in C:\Application 
						Data\vulcan.  This is probably not what you want, so you can either
						configure the Apache Tomcat service to run as some other user, or
						change Vulcan's configRoot.
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>Linux, OS X, Unix</td>
					<td class="location">$HOME/vulcan</td>
					<td>
						Configuration data will go in a subdirectory named <span class="filename">vulcan</span>
						under the home directory of the user running
						Apache Tomcat, e.g. <span class="filename">/home/joe/vulcan</span>.
					</td>
				</tr>
			</tbody>
		</table>
		<p>
			If you want Vulcan to use a different location, find the <span class="configKey">configRoot</span>
			property in <span class="filename">beans.xml</span> and change the <span class="configKey">value</span>
			to your desired location.
		</p>
	</section>
  </body>
</document>
